rainbownation.com 2006-12-27

# The RainbowNation.com Privacy Statement

|  |  | 

You are here: Home > Services > Privacy 

(last updated: July 2004)

RainbowNation is committed to protecting your privacy. This RainbowNation Privacy Statement applies to data collection and usage on RainbowNation sites and services; it does not apply to other online or offline RainbowNation sites, products or services. Please read the RainbowNation Privacy Statement below and also any supplementary information at the end of this statement for additional details about particular RainbowNation sites and services that you may use.

RainbowNation is a general audience web site, intended for users of all ages. Personal information of all users is collected, used and disclosed as described in this Privacy Statement. This Statement contains a section with specific details regarding personal information collected from children. Click  here to read more.

## Collection of your Personal Information

At some sites, RainbowNation collects personal information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. RainbowNation may also collect demographic information, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favourites. Information collected by RainbowNation may be combined with information obtained from other RainbowNation services and other companies.

If you choose to sign up for a paid subscription service, we will collect additional personal information, including your credit card number and billing address, in order to create a RainbowNation billing account.

Some RainbowNation services, such as Forums, Blogs or Groups, request that you create a social nickname, which is the name you will be known by to others in those public places. You may select a different social nickname at any time. You can also choose to create an optional public profile, containing information about yourself - such as your hobbies and interests. Any information you choose to enter in your public profile will be visible to other users of RainbowNation sites and services; and when you interact with other users (for example, sending an email message to another email account or interacting in a RainbowNation Forum), a link to your public profile may be displayed. Please keep in mind that if you disclose personal information through these public online forums, this information may be collected and used by others. RainbowNation cautions you against providing personal information to strangers online, which they may use for illegal or harmful purposes.

RainbowNation keeps track of the pages our customers visit within RainbowNation, in order to determine what RainbowNation sites and services are the most popular.

RainbowNation also collects certain information about your computer hardware and software. This information may include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses.

Certain RainbowNation services may be co-branded and offered in conjunction with another company. If you register for or use such services, both RainbowNation and the other company may receive information collected in conjunction with the co-branded services.

RainbowNation and its operational service partners collect and use your personal information to operate RainbowNation and deliver the services you have requested. These services may include the display of customized content and advertising based upon the information RainbowNation has collected. RainbowNation does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

RainbowNation also uses your personal information to inform you of other products or services available from RainbowNation and its affiliates. RainbowNation may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

RainbowNation does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. RainbowNation may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your personal information (e-mail, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. 

We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as handling the processing and delivery of mailings, providing customer support, processing transactions, or performing statistical analysis of our services. We will only provide those companies the personal information they need to deliver the service. They are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information and are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

RainbowNation may access and/or disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on RainbowNation or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of RainbowNation, including its RainbowNation family of Web sites; or (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of RainbowNation services or members of the public.

Personal information collected on this site may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which RainbowNation or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities, and by using this site, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. RainbowNation abides by the safe harbour framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union.

## Control of your Personal Information

RainbowNation offers its customers choices for the collection, use and sharing of personal information. You may choose not to receive marketing material from RainbowNation or on behalf of external third party business partners. You may also stop the delivery of future promotional e-mail from RainbowNation by following the specific instructions in the e-mail you receive. The instructions explain how to stop receiving such e-mails.

There are some RainbowNation services, that send out periodic e-mails informing you of technical service issues, product surveys, new feature announcements and news about RainbowNation products and services. You will not be able to unsubscribe to these mailings, as they are considered a part of the service you have chosen.

You may subscribe and unsubscribe to RainbowNation Newsletters and each RainbowNation newsletter you receive will have instructions on how to unsubscribe prominently mentioned in it.

## Security of your Personal Information

RainbowNation is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer systems with limited access, which are located in controlled facilities. When we transmit highly confidential information (such as a credit card number) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

## Collection and Use of Children's Personal Information

The RainbowNation site is intended for users of all ages. Children may visit these general audience areas of RainbowNation and provide personal information, which will be collected, used and disclosed as described is this Privacy Statement. Some, but not all, RainbowNation sites require users to provide age information. For those users who visit such sites and identify themselves as under 13, RainbowNation will not collect any of their information.

**Please note that if you grant consent for your child to use such general audience communication services your child will be able to communicate with other users of all ages. Before providing consent, please be aware that such services will give your child the ability to disclose personal information (e.g. name, address, e-mail, phone numbers) on his or her own.** We encourage you to talk with your children about communicating with strangers and disclosing personal information online. 

## Use of Cookies

RainbowNation uses "cookies" to help you personalise your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. For example, if you personalize RainbowNation's pages, or register with RainbowNation sites or services, a cookie helps RainbowNation to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, preferred email address, and so on. When you return to RainbowNation, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the RainbowNation features that you customised.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the RainbowNation services or Web sites you visit. 

## Use of Web Beacons

RainbowNation Web pages may contain electronic images known as Web beacons - sometimes called single-pixel gifs - that allow RainbowNation to count users who have visited those pages and to deliver co-branded services. RainbowNation may include web beacons in promotional e-mail messages or RainbowNation Newsletters in order to count how many messages have been opened and acted upon.

Web beacons collect only a limited set of information including a cookie number, time and date of a page view, and a description of the page on which the Web beacon resides. RainbowNation Web pages may also contain Web beacons placed there by third parties in order to compile aggregated statistics and to help determine the effectiveness of our joint promotional or advertising campaigns. RainbowNation prohibits web beacons from being used to access your personal information.

## Use of Third Party Ad Networks

The majority of the online banner advertisements you see on RainbowNation Web pages are displayed by RainbowNation.

In addition, RainbowNation allows other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to display advertisements on RainbowNation Web pages. Some of these ad networks may place a persistent cookie on your computer. Doing this allows the ad network to recognise your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad networks may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. RainbowNation does not have access to or control of the cookies that may be placed by the third-party ad servers or ad networks.

## Changes to this Statement

RainbowNation will occasionally update this Privacy Statement to reflect company and customer feedback. If there are material changes to this Statement or in how RainbowNation will use your personal information, RainbowNation will prominently post such changes prior to implementing the change. RainbowNation encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how RainbowNation is protecting your information. |
